# Reid Souchereau

# **About**

Insight-driven, published graduate researcher with a focus in machine learning. Motivated to improve health and safety with novel machine learning algorithms. I am currently applying deep learning time series algorithms to bypass the need for EMGs to measure muscle activity. Pre and post print publications in the areas of deep learning, exoskeletons, IMUs, and biomaterials. Coursework experience in computer vision, statistics, cognitive systems, human computer interaction, neuroscience, and epidemiology. A reliable, creative, and *adaptable* team leader.

# **Education**

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH - 3.952 GPA

Master of Science, Integrated Systems Engineering, Present

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH - 3.56 GPA

Bachelor of Science, Biomedical Engineering, May. 2020

# **Experience**

Graduate Research Associate, Spine Research Institute - The Ohio State University.

Feb. 2020 - Present

- Research interest in deep learning solutions for wearable sensing, biomechanics, 3D modeling, health tracking, and medical diagnosis
- Deep learning model development and integration for various applications within spine biomechanical evaluation software with Tensorflow
  - Includes creating data pipelines for model training and evaluation
- Collect, process, and analyze both subject motion capture, IMUs, and various sensors as inputs to spine biomechanical model software
- Statistical analysis of human subject biomechanical data
- Conduct literature reviews, manuscript drafting, proposal drafting, and present publications at research symposiums
- Consult with external companies to assess industrial safety using lab spine biomechanical models and wearable technologies

#### Senior Capstone Project.

Aug. 2019 - May. 2020

- Developed vehicle swivel seat to allow persons with Parkinson's disease to safely enter and exit car with ease
- Performed a kinematic assessment of sitting and standing from vehicle to determine design requirements
- Create 3D CAD model for crash test validation in ANSYS using NHTSA Standards

# IT Student Assistant, The Ohio State University Library IT.

May. 2019 - May. 2020

• Software and network support / computer imaging and installation

# **Undergraduate Research Assistant, Advanced Ceramics Research Laboratory - The Ohio State University.**

Jan. 2018 – Jan. 2019

- Preliminary research on development of an amyloid fiber scalable production process for water treatment and melatonin sensing
- Antibody allergen sensing for research report which was used as part of a joint funding proposal

#### Personal info

#### Phone:

614-226-2998

#### Email:

souchereau.1@osu.edu

#### Address:

1531 Neil Ave Apt D, Columbus, OH 43201

#### LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/reidsouchereau

#### Portfolio:

reidsouchereau.org

#### ResearchGate:

https://www.researchgate.net/profile/ Reid Souchereau

# **Skills**

# **Python**



#### **Technical Writing**



### Microsoft Office



# Adaptability



#### Research



#### **Critical Thinking**



# Biomechanics

